Finding Aid for Migrant Health Promotion records, 1982-2012
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical files
  - Migrant Health
    - Nutrition Education Materials, Spanish/English undated (Box 9)
  - National Migrant Resource Program, Inc. 1991 Migrant Health Centers Referral Directory (Box 9)
  - Outreach Guidance 1992 (Box 9)
  - Publications About Migrant Workers
    - "The Migration of Mexican-American Agricultural Labor into Wood County, Ohio", Wade A. Chio 1970 (Box 9)
    - "Seven Families", Joy Hintz 1976 (Box 9)
    - "Minority Health in Michigan; Closing the Gap", Michigan Department of Public Health 1988 (Box 9)
    - "The Politics of Health Policy on Migrants", Rosemary Berchem 1984 (Box 9)
  - "Short Biographies of the MMHIO Advisory Council Members" (includes photos) (Box 9)
  - "Task Force on Collaboration in Migrant Health," 1984-1987 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous 1984, 2009 undated (Box 9)
- Photographs
  The Photographs series is primarily composed of albums documenting the Camp Health Aide program. This series also includes 32 mounted photographs taken for the Camp Health Aide Photovoice project by teenage health aides, depicting camp and community life at DuRussel's Potato Farms, Washtenaw County, Mich.
  - La Voz Latina Program 2008 (Box 9)
  - Migrant Health Promotion 1993-2000, photograph album (Box 9)
  - Migrant Health Promotion Texas 2007, photograph album (Box 9)
  - Staff (Box 9)
  - Camp Health Aide
    - 2006 (Box 9)
    - Nutrition CHAP 2007 (Box 9)
    - Teen Aides 1998-2001 (Box 9)
    - 1986-1989, photograph album (Box 10)
    - Shelby CHAP 1993, photograph album (Box 10)
    - 1999-2001, photograph album (Box 10)
    - Indiana CHA undated, photograph album (Box 10)
    - Wild Rose Clinic (Wild Rose, WI) 1989-1991, 2 photograph albums (Box 10)
    - Photo slides
      - Illinois Camp Health Aide Program 1997 (Box 10)
      - The National Migrant Worker Council 1979-1982 (Box 10)
    - Photovoice project 2009, 32 mounted photographs (Box 11)
  - Contact sheets 1993, 2008 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous late 1980s-2008 (Box 14)
  - Negatives 1994, undated (Box 14)
- Videotapes
  The Videotapes series consists of copies of the two promotional videos produced by MMHIO and producers, Harnack & Company of Mission Viejo, California: Harvest of Hope: The Camp Health Aide Program (1989) and The Camp Health Aide Program; A Personal Perspective (1990). Included in addition are two subseries of unedited footage used in the production of the videos. The first, filmed in Texas, consists of interviews with camp health aides and their families. The videos include interviews about daily life and the importance of the camp health aide program to the individuals involved. There are tours of the migrant's home in Texas and a church service. The second subseries was filmed in Sparta, Michigan and consists of an interview with a doctor at the local migrant community health center, interviews with camp health aides, and shots of the migrant camps showing children playing and workers in the field. After cursory examination, it appears that the two final productions contain parts of both of the subseries of unedited film. The Miscellaneous subseries includes an interview, educational sessions, and the "Models that Work" video, which highlights the Camp Health Aide Program. All are VHS unless otherwise noted.
  - Camp Health Aide Program videos
    - Harvest of Hope; The Camp Health Aide Program 1989 (Box 12)
    - The Camp Health Aide Program; A Personal Perspective 1990 (Box 12)
    - Unedited footage used in production of the videos "Harvest of Hope" and "The Camp Health Aide Program"
      - Numbered videos: Migrant workers in Texas, 14 videotapes VHS (TM)
        - Tour of Home of Marie Inez Perez (a camp health aide) April 18, 1989 (Box 12)
          (tape nos. 1-5)
        - Outside Perez home in Texas, preparing lunch, doing laundry (Box 12)
          (tape no. 6)
        - Daughter Ruby comes home and talks (Box 12)
          (tape no. 7)
        - Ruby in her room (Box 12)
          (tape no. 8)
        - Daughter Esmeralda talking in her room (Box 12)
          (tape no. 9)
        - Church service (Box 12)
          (tape no. 10)
        - Interview with young couple talking about migrant life and her work as camp health aide (Box 12)
          (tape nos. 11-14)
      - Numbered videos: Migrant farm workers, Sparta, Michigan, 17 videotapes VHS (TM)
        - Discussion of Migrant Camp Health Aide program with doctor at community heath center in Sparta, Michigan (Box 12)
          (tape no. 201-03)
        - Interview of Migrant Health Care Aide at the Sparta migrant camp (Box 12)
          (tape no. 204-06)
        - Interview with another aide (Box 12)
          (tape no. 207-09)
        - Children playing in camp, exterior views of camp life; interview with Inez Perez about proposed day-care facility in Oceana County. (Box 12)
          (tape no. 210-12)
        - Migrants in fields; interview with them about the camp health aide program (Box 12)
          (tape no. 215-17)
  - Miscellaneous Tapes, 15 videotapes VHS (TM); 1 videotapes Mini-DV
    - Migrant Health Promotion, 4 tapes (Box 13)
      (tape nos. 1-4)
    - Somewhere to Turn: Community and Migrant Health Centers Story 1990s (Box 13)
      (tape no. 5)
    - Migrant Lay Health Programs: Their Role and Impact, 199? (Box 13)
      (tape no.6)
    - Nuestra Salud (Box 13)
      DVD-RW
    - Nuestra Salud La Menopausia (Box 13)
    - Nuestra Salud El Examen Annual, DVD-RW (Box 13)
    - Maria Irma's Educational Session Cambria, Pre-Natal (Box 13)
    - Interview with Sr. Maurita (Box 13)
    - Bianca's Education Session Cameria, Part 1; L.P.C. Training with June (Box 13)
      (tape no. 11)
    - Bianca's Educational Session Cameria, Part 2; Personal Hygiene, Part II (Box 13)
      (tape no. 12)
    - Group Educational Sessions, Wisconsin 8/1992 MMH10 10th Year Celebration, Texas, 2/1993 labeled 7, 1992-1993 (Box 13)
      (tape no. 13)
    - Bureau of Primary Health Care Video featuring MHP CHAP in Mercedes, TX (Box 13)
      (tape no. 14)
    - Models That Work 1996 (Box 13)
      (tape no. 15)
    - Promotora Talk Show January 31, 2004, Mini Digital Video Cassette (Box 13)
      (tape no.16)
- Sound Recordings
  The Sound Recordings series contains one audiocassette, which is a recording of a radio interview with Alejandra Gonzales.
  - Radio Interview with Alejandra Gonzales (NPR-All Things Considered CHAP-Farmworkers-Mental Health) 8/2001, 1 audiocassettes (Box 13)